Now, note that we can decide what radial basis functions to use.
现在 我们可以选择一种径向基函数
We can use some very wide ones or some very narrow ones. How do we decide?
是选择陡峭的还是平缓的 要如何决定呢？
Well, this is a hyper parameter that we tune
这就是我们在训练中需要调整的超参数
during training and it is called the gamma parameter.
它被称为伽马参数（γ）
And in a nutshell, a large gamma will move us a narrow curve like the one on the left,
简言之 γ 越大 曲线越陡 如左图
and a small gamma would give us a wide curve like this one in the right.
γ 越小 曲线越平缓 如右图
In higher dimensions, this is very similar.
在高维度下也很相似
A large gamma will give us some pointy mountains like the one on the left,
一个大的 γ 参数会带来呈尖顶状的山型 如左图
and a small one would give us mountains looking like the one in the right.
而小的 γ 参数则会带来像右图展示的山型
And this choice of gamma actually matters a lot in the algorithm.
在算法中 γ 的选择至关重要
Picture looking at your data from above or after the projection.
想象一下俯视这些数据 或者将它们投射到平面
If you used a bunch of skinny mountains,
如果你使用的是陡峭的山型
then your boundary will look like the one on the left where
那你的边界会像左图中显示的一样
most points have their own little piece of boundary surrounding them.
大多数点的周围都有一圈小小的边界
If you use wider mountains,
如果你使用比较平缓的山型
then you would end up with something like the boundary in the right.
那你会得到如右图所示的边界
And as you can see from the picture,
从图中你可以看到
large values of gamma tend to overfit,
γ 值过大会导致过拟合
and small ones tend to underfit.
而 γ 值过小则会欠拟合
And now, what is Gamma?
那么 什么是 γ 呢？
Well, here's where we define with these radial basis functions are.
这是我们用径向基函数定义的地方
We'll use the Gaussian or normal distribution for this.
为此我们会用到高斯分布或正态分布
The Gaussian is a very well-used function in statistics that has this formula,
在统计学中 高斯函数是一个很好用的函数
y equals one over a square root of
它的公式是 y 等于
two pi times E to the power of negative x squared over two.
1 除以根号 2π 乘以 E 的 -x²/2 次方
In the general case, when you have a distribution of min mu in standard deviation sigma,
大多数情况下 当你在标准差 σ 中有一个最小分布 μ
the formula is this,
公式就成了这样
where mu is the very center of the curve,
μ 就是曲线的原点
and sigma is related to its width.
而 σ 则与曲线宽度相关
So if sigma is large,
也就是说 如果 σ 大
then the curve is very wide,
则曲线会非常宽
and if sigma is small,
而如果 σ 小
then the curve is very narrow.
则曲线非常狭窄
So in order to define gamma,
因此 为定义γ
we just use one divided by two sigma squared.
我们只需使用图左的公式即可
Notice that if gamma is large,
需要注意的是 如果 γ 大
then sigma is small,
则 σ 小
so the curve is narrow, and vice versa.
曲线会较狭窄 反之亦然
If gamma is small, then sigma is large and the curve is wide.
如果 γ 小 则 σ 大 曲线较宽
In the higher dimensional case,
在高维情况下
this formula becomes a little more complicated.
此公式会稍微复杂些
But as long as we think of gamma as some parameter that is
但只要我们把 γ 当做与曲线宽度相关
associated with the width of the curve in an inverse way,
且呈反比的一个参数
then we are grasping the concept of the gamma parameter and the RBF kernel.
我们就抓住了 γ 参数及径向基核函数的概念